Privacy Policy
==============

Last Updated: November 25, 2022

Welcome to Better Stack, Inc. (**“we”**, **“us”** or **“Better Stack”**). We provide monitoring and logging tools to our users (**“you”**). To provide our Services we need to collect some of your personal data, whether you are using https://betterstack.com/ (**“Site”**) or are using our platform (**“Platform”**) collectively our **“Services”**. This Privacy Policy (the **“Privacy Policy”**) is intended to inform you about our practices regarding the collection and use of your data that you may submit to us through our Services. This Privacy Policy should be read alongside, and in addition to the Terms of Use.

Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used have the same meaning as in the Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy may be updated to reflect changes in legislation, so please review it now and then. You can always find the most recent version on our Site. If we make substantial changes, we will try to provide a notice prior to any changes taking effect. What constitutes a substantial change will be determined at our sole discretion. By continuing to access or use our Service after those revisions become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised terms. If you do not agree to the new terms, please stop using the Services.

The Privacy Policy only covers data processing carried out by us. The Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy practices of any other parties.

We do not knowingly collect or ask for information from people under the age of 18. If you are such a person, please do not use our service or send us your information. We delete information that we learn is collected from a person under the age of 18 without verified parental consent.

Who processes your data
-----------------------

Your data is being processed by our company **Better Stack, Inc.**, a Delaware corporation (**“Better Stack”**, **“we”**, **“us”** or **“our”**).

To learn more about data management or if you have any other questions, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://betterstack.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

What data is processed
----------------------

We may collect the following types of information about you:

### Personal Identifiable Information

Through our Services, we may collect and process information that can be used to identify or contact you as an individual known as your personal identifiable information (“PII”), including but not limited to:

* first and second names
* email address
* professional experience
* and other PII provided by you voluntarily when you use our Services

### Technical Information

We and/or our authorised external service providers may automatically collect technical data when you visit or interact with our Services. Technical data may include, in particular:

* the URL of the site visited before using our Service
* the time and date of user visits
* IP address
* the browser name and type
* the type of computer or device accessing our Service
* time spent on the Service and other similar technical information

In a limited number of cases it is possible to use technical data and identify you as an individual, thus making them PII, however, we never use technical data to identify you as an individual.

We use technical data to:

* Provide, operate, and maintain our Services
* Improve, personalize, and expand our Services
* Understand and analyze how you use our Services
* Develop new products, services, features, and functionality
* Communicate with you, either directly or through one of our partners, including for customer service
* To provide you with updates and other information relating to the Services, and for marketing and promotional purposes
* Send you emails
* Find and prevent fraud

### Cookies

We use cookies to collect information about your activity across our Services. A cookie is a small piece of data that the Service saves on your device each time you visit.

We use our cookies to remember your actions and preferences so you don’t have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the Site or browse from one page to another.

We also use cookies for analytics purposes and to help us personalize your experience and improve our Services.

As mentioned above, in some cases we also may use cookies provided by third parties (service providers). The list of such third-parties cookies of which you might encounter through our service is listed below. We are not responsible for third-party sites and their privacy practices. These companies collect and use this information under their own privacy policies and are responsible for their practices concerning cookies.

You can change your cookie preferences in your browser settings.

What are the purposes and legal basis for processing your PII?
--------------------------------------------------------------

We process your PII in order to:

**Provide our Services to you.** This purpose includes mainly the following processing activities:

* creating and providing your account from PII you provide upon registration;
* informing you about updates and new features of our Service;
* notifying you about updates of our Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy;
* responding to you in relation to any queries you may have with respect to our Services;
* resolving potential agreement-related troubleshooting problems and disputes.

We process the email address, payment information and other data provided by you voluntarily when you use our Service.

**Process an application as part of Better Stack’s recruitment.** During our application process we may collect and process the applicant’s name, contact details and professional background.

**Market our Services.** We may market our current or future Services if you subscribe to our newsletter on our Site and by doing so, you provide us your consent with the processing of your email address for the marketing purposes.

There are several ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us: click the “Unsubscribe” link in any email communication that we send you, or withdraw your consent through [\[email protected\]](https://betterstack.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Improve our Services.** This purpose includes the following processing activities using technical information:

* to influence current and future features;
* to prevent and detect security flaws and user interface issues.

How we share your personal data
-------------------------------

We only share your PII within Better Stack and with those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that need to know the information in order to process it on Better Stack’s behalf or to provide the Services and those that that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

We do not share your PII with other recipients unless one of the following circumstances applies:

**It is necessary for the compliance with our obligations towards you.** To the extent that our external service providers (sub-processors) need access to your PII to help us perform our Services for you, we have taken the appropriate contractual and organizational measures to ensure that your PII are processed in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations.

A full list of our sub-processors is found in our [DPA](https://betterstack.com/dpa).

The list of external service providers we use may change from time to time as we change or remove some of the providers listed above and/or put in place other providers to assist us in providing the Services.

**It is necessary for legal reasons.** We may share your PII with recipients outside of Better Stack if we have a good-faith belief that access to and use of your PII is reasonably necessary to: (i) meet any applicable law, regulation, and/or court order; (ii) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; and/or (iii) protect the interests, properties or safety of Better Stack, our users or the public as far as in accordance with the law. When possible, we will inform you about such processing.

Where do we transfer your data to
---------------------------------

We process personal data primarily in the European Union. However, our Services are governed by and operated in, and in accordance with the laws of the United States and are intended for the enjoyment of residents of the United States.

If you use our Services and are a European resident, you acknowledge and agree that your PII may be transmitted outside of the European Economic Area. In such a case, we transfer your personal data only to a country that is considered to have an adequate level of protection in accordance with the EU Commission's decision or there are appropriate safeguards in place to protect your personal data, such as standard contractual clauses or binding internal company rules. Regardless of the country in which your personal data is processed, we take reasonable technical, legal and organizational measures to ensure that the level of protection is the same as in the European Union and the European Economic Area.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition or other reorganization, your information may be transferred as part of that deal. We will notify you (for example, via a message to the email address associated with your account) of any such deal and outline your choices in that event.

What is the storage period
--------------------------

Better Stack stores your PII only if it is legally permitted and necessary for the purposes for which the data were collected or we are legally obliged to do so.

Better Stack as a Data Processor
--------------------------------

While using our Services, you may be providing us with your clients’ data, including PII such as name and email address. You are the controller or primary processor with regard to the processing of relevant PII. Better Stack shall process PII only as a processor or sub-processor (as applicable to your use of the Services).

More information regarding our data processing as a processor can be found in our [Data Processing Agreement](https://betterstack.com/dpa).

California Consumer Privacy Act Notice
--------------------------------------

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your PII to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Moreover, you have the right to restrict the sharing of your PII and with our affiliates (companies we own or control) and outside companies with whom we do business.

We are aware of your rights afforded to California residents under the California Consumer Privacy Act (the “CCPA”). Even though the CCPA does not apply to us now, we are ready to protect your PII and give you an option to exercise your right under CCPA once it becomes applicable.

To contact us with questions about our rights under California privacy laws, email us at [\[email protected\]](https://betterstack.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Your rights
-----------

**Right of access.** Better Stack offers you access to your PII we process. This means you can contact us and request from us a confirmation whether or not your PII are being processed and if so, you have the right to request access to your data, which we will provide to you in the form of a so-called "registry" (stating, in particular, purposes, categories of personal data, categories of recipients of personal data, storage periods or criteria for determining storage periods).

**Right to erasure.** You may also ask us to erase your PII from our systems. We will comply with such requests unless we have a legitimate ground to not delete your personal data.

**Right to restriction of processing.** You may request us to restrict certain processing of your personal data. If you restrict certain processing of your personal data, this may lead to fewer possibilities to use our Services and Site.

**How to use your rights.** You may exercise your rights above, free of charge, in writing by sending a letter or email at [\[email protected\]](https://betterstack.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We may require confirmation of your identity depending on your request.

Data security
-------------

We take all reasonable, appropriate security measures to protect our customers from unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of PII we hold. Measures include, where appropriate, encryption, firewalls, secure facilities and access rights systems. Should despite the security measures, a security breach occur that is likely to have negative effects to your privacy, we will inform you about the breach as soon as reasonably possible. If you have any questions, feel free to contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://betterstack.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
